# **Software Programmer**

# **ROHITH REDDY**

+91 888 654 0155

rohithreddy.github.io

rohithreddy

rohithreddyt@yandex.com

# **EXPERIENCE**

## N!yo

#### Data Engineer | June 2017 - April 2018

### RedBlackTree

#### **Serverside IOT Engineer** | October 2016 - February 2017

## Sphota Biz

#### Member of Technical Staff | September 2018 - August 2019

#### **Customer Centria**

#### Full-stack Developer | July 2015 - August 2016

Created campaign analytics dashboard in Backbone.js Single Page Application, integrating d3.js and nvd3.js libraries into Omni-channel Campaign management SaaS product, wrote REST API's for aggregating statistics from campaigns with Spring and MongoDB

Used Jenkins to create a CI / CD pipeline and automated reliable deployments
Proposed and managed a Mesos cluster for running applications and data workloads, increasing developer productivity making deployments more resilient and manageable
Implemented a resilient pipeline to capture tweets based on keywords related to clients & perform sentiment analysis for a customer 360 data application with help from data scientists, senior developers. Used Kafka, Python, MongoDB running on the Mesos Cluster

## **EDUCATION**

# Major in Physics with Honors, BITS Pilani University, India

Master of Science | August 2009 - March 2015

## **SKILLS**

### About me

A Programmer with 4+ years of experience in building Data Intensive Applications that are simple and functional, tackling challenging architectural and scalability problems. In my free time I am either hacking Linux kernel or building embedded IoT devices.